María Alejandra Pérez

UX / UI Designer

mapb1989@gmail.com

Barcelona, Spain

+34677709274

linkedin.com/in/mapb1989 in

mariaalejandraperez.com **@**

About me

UX / UI Designer with a background in engineering. My experience has taught me how to communicate with stakeholders, provide timely solutions for support incidences, and design processes that understand the customer's struggles and motivations. All of these lessons have inspired me and have made me focused on UX design.

Education

12/2019 – 06/2020 **UX/UI Designer**

Ironhack (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2014 - 02/2017 Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2007 – 12/2012 **Electronic Engineer**

Universidad Simón Bolívar (Caracas, Venezuela)

Projects

O5-06/2020 App for streaming services recommendations

UX/UI Final Project at Ironhack (UX Research, IA, Interaction design, UI Design.)

Goal: Offer accurate recommendations for movies and shows streaming services.

Other projects can be found at mariaalejandraperez.com

Work Experience

05/2018 - 04/2020

Lead Customer Support Engineer

Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

Software provider of Smart WiFi and proximity marketing

- Manage support team and helping clients with any issues regarding the performance and configuration of their access point and routers.
- Analyze, improve and maintain the company's operational processes.
- Report, replicate and track bugs in the production environment.

04/2016 – 05/2018

Support and Presales Engineer

Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

- Manage customers' projects from contract signature to end of installation.
- Provide training and support to customers as required.



Technologies: Figma | Sketch | Adobe XD | Invision | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin **Hard Skills:** Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design **Soft Skills:** Problem solving | Adaptability | Time management | Empathy | Listening

Languages

Spanish: Native German: Intermediate
English: Proficient Catalan: Beginner